Part Three: Supportive Measures
If you do experience weight
loss due to difficulty with nutrition,
we can help with supportive measures.
First,
we can make adjustments to your diet
by adding foods that are easier
to consume, such as softer foods.
Our dietitian will help
you look at pureed food
or soft foods that are dense in nutrition.
Second,
we have numbing agents such as lidocaine
to soften
the pain caused by swallowing food.
Lidocaine, which you can rinse around
in your mouth and swallow, also known as
rinse and swallow,
will numb your mouth and throat
for about 15 to 20 minutes.
This short window provides you
an opportunity to eat as much as you can,
with the decrease in pain
caused by irritating the inflamed tissues
of the mouth and throat.